Guide to the Angela Shelf Medearis Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Articles, 1987-1995, undated
  - Texas Black Public Colleges (Buryin' Jim Crow in Texas), undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Who's Crazy (Box 17, Folder 23)
- Plays, 1998
  This series contains drafts and performance photographs of Medearis' plays.
  - Five Women: A One Woman Show About Five Inspiring Women (typescript and performance photos) (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Pecos Bill and Slue-Foot Sue (typescript draft) (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Poetry, 1987-1996, undated
  Poetry, includes mostly undated typescripts, few handwritten drafts. Many files include a single version of a poem, and some include multiple annotated drafts. The bulk of the poems seem to date from late 1980s. They are arranged alphabetically.
  - Ageless (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Black Patent Pumps (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Borrowing the Aura (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Bumper Psychology (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Chemical Reaction (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Confession (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Cycle (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Easy Lover (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Enslumberances (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Expose (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Feelings Left Unspoken (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Ghost Town (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Hair Strokes (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Have Mercy (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Higher Education (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Hot House Flower (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - I Love You (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Innocent (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Interpretation (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Jogger's Lament (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - The Jr. Miss Beauty Pageant (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Just a Trim Please (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - A Little Common Sense (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - A Little Romance (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Mask (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Match (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Me and You (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Neon (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Physical Fitness (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Poem for My Little, Big Sister (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Progress (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Resistance (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Rock & Roll Boys (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Search Party (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Secret (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Stress Relief (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - The Sweet Smell of Success (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Unity poem (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Ups and Downs (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - The Year White Folks Got Rhythm (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Untitled and fragments (Box 18, Folder 43)
- Video Projects, 1996-1999
  Proposals, script treatments, correspondence, and notes represent the creation and development of Medearis' video projects. Materials have been arranged in chronological order, beginning with the earliest dates
  - Di the Daydreamer - Treatment, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Kitchen Divas - Treatment proposal and correspondence, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - The Inheritance - Treatment, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - Kulture Klash - TV sitcom, Treatment and correspondence, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - Waking Up Screaming - Script, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - Perfect Attendance - Treatment, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - Always a Bridesmaid - Docudrama - Screenplay, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 50)
  - Always a Bridesmaid - Docudrama - Promotional flyer, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 51)
  - Texas Junior Audubon Society - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 52)
  - Texas Junior Audubon Society - Publicity flyer (oversize), 1999 (Box 36, Folder 9)
- Unidentified works, undated
  Notes for unidentified projects.
  - Unidentified notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 53)
- Correspondence, 1984-2000, undated
  This series has been divided into the following subseries: A. Letters from Children (1989-1999), B. Publisher correspondence (1987-2000), C. Author visits / appearances (1988-2000), and D. General (1984-2000). Each of these subseries has been arranged chronologically by year.
  Letters from Children generally include letters from schoolchildren thanking Medearis for visiting their school as an author/storyteller, some wrote to ask about her writing career or personal life. Includes one undated oversize card from Medearis' granddaughter, Anysa.
  Publisher correspondence includes interaction between Medearis and the various publishing company staff editors, advertising agents, and special event planners. Some letters relate to specific titles, while others relate to several titles or to Medearis' career in general.
  Subseries C. Author visits / appearances, includes requests, confirmations, and thank you notes related to storytelling visits and appearances made by Medearis at schools, reading groups, and other locations. General correspondence does not fall into any of these categories, and tends to include topics such as professional memberships, fundraising. It also includes early correspondence related to Medearis pre-writing career.
  - Letters from Children, 1989-1999, undated
    - 1989 (Box 18, Folder 54)
    - 1990 (Box 18, Folder 55)
    - 1991 (Box 18, Folder 56)
    - 1992 (Box 18, Folder 57)
    - 1993 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - 1994 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - 1995 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - 1996 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - 1997 (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
    - 1998 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - 1999 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Publishers, 1987-2000, undated
    - 1987 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - 1988 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - 1989 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - 1990 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - 1991 (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
    - 1992 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - 1993 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - 1994 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - 1995 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - 1996 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - 1997 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - 1998 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - 1999 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - 2000 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Reject Letters (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Agent / Attorney, 1987-1997 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Author Visits / Appearances, 1988-2000, undated
    - 1988 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - 1989 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - 1990 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - 1991 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - 1992 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - 1993 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - 1994 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - 1995 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - 1996 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - 1997 (Box 24, Folder 2-3)
    - 1998 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - 1999 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - 2000 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - undated (Box 25, Folder 2-3)
  - General, 1984-2000, undated
    - 1984-1987 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - 1989 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - 1990 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - 1991 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - 1992 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - 1993 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - 1994 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - 1995 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - 1996 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - 1997 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - 1998 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - 1999 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - 2000 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Subject Files, 1983-1996, undated
  Clippings, correspondence, pamphlets, and information packets related to subjects of interest to Medearis comprise this series. The files have been arranged in alphabetical order by subject file name.
  - African American Reading List (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Austin Romance Writers, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Austin Writers' League, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Authors Guild, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Black Arts Alliance, 1983-1989 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Black Business Alliance, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Carver Museum, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Center for Multicultural Children's Literature, 1992-1993 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Children's games, undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Children's Radio Bookmobile, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Daily Newspapers of Texas (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - F.E.P., Inc. newsletter, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Home Shopping Network, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - International Reading Association, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Kwanzaa (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Multicultural literature (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - National Council for the Social Studies (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - National Council of Teachers of English (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - National Endowment for the Arts - application, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Order forms - for Medearis' books (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Peabody Ducks (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Photo file - copy prints of W.E.B. DuBois, Scott Joplin, and others (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Red Tails (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Reading is Fundamental, 1993-1994 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Romance Writers of America (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Seminars - writing seminars by Medearis and publicity for other seminars, 1992-1994 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Society of Children's Book Writers and Illustrators, 1989-1996 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Storytelling- bibliographies and info on Medearis' presentations (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
  - Texas Institute of Letters, 1993-1996 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - T. V. Busters (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Texas Library Association (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Texas Monthly Press - catalogs and memos from Medearis' employment at TM Press, 1987-1989 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Texas Poison Control, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Three Ring Circus, 1989-1990 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Travel (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Travel - completed (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Work of Art - gifts (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Writers Guild of America (Box 29, Folder 4)
- Clippings, 1987-2001, undated
  Many of the newsclippings in this series are about Medearis, others simply represent her interests. Clippings have been arranged in chronological order by year.
  - 1987 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - 1988 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - 1989 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - 1990 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - 1991 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - 1992 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - 1993 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - 1994 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - 1995 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - 1996 (Box 30, Folder 8, Box 31, Folder 1)
  - 1997 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Clipping of Texas Monthly article on Medearis mounted as a plaque (two pieces), 1997 (Box 35)
  - 1998 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - 1999 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - 2000 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - 2001 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - The Washington Post newspaper Presidential inaugural edition featuring Medearis, 2001 (Box 35)
  - undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
- Publicity, 1988-1999, undated
  This series is comprised of biographical notes, resumes, book catalogs, correspondence, mailing lists, and photographs related to the commercial promotion of Medearis' books
  - Biographical notes, resumes, circa 1990-1995 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Advertisements, catalogs, circa 1993-1999 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence- regarding Children's Bookmobile, Eyebeam cartoon publicity through TM Press, general children's books publicity, 1988, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - 1985-1996 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - undated (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Mailing lists (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Photos - including color snapshots of Medearis, formerly attached to large posterboard, undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Notes (Box 32, Folder 9)
- Awards, 1991-1996
  Includes correspondence regarding awards and honors received, as well as those applied for and not received. Includes certificate for Teddy Children's Book Award, 1996.
  - 1991-1996 (Box 33, Folder 1)
- Calendars, 1996-1997
  This series includes a calendar from 1996 and one from 1997. Each calendar notes daily appointments, while some months contain no information.
  - Includes clippings and notes, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - 1997 (Box 33, Folder 3)
- Photographs, 1987, undated
  Photographs taken by Medearis or other unidentified photographers comprise the bulk of this series. Formats for these images include color and black and white slides, photoprints, and negatives. Photographs of Medearis and her family are present in color and black and white print formats
  - Photos of Medearis and family, including poster featuring black and white Medearis family photos (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Photos by Medearis of others (Box 33, Folder 5)
- Personal Programs, 1987-1992
  Correspondence, videotapes, and clippings relate to Medearis' involvement in Book Boosters, Children's Radio Bookmobile, and Special Sitters.
  - Book Boosters / Children's Radio Bookmobile - Correspondence, 1991-1992, undated (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Book Boosters / Children's Radio Bookmobile - Two promotional videos (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Special Sitters - correspondence and clippings related to this program developed by First Texas Council of Camp Fire and promoted by Medearis, 1987, undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
- Artworks, undated
  This series includes three color renderings of various subjects, by unidentified child and adult artists, with the exception of one piece by 4th grade student Ravi Nair.
  - One alligator and one lion drawing, undated (Map-case Drawer 19)
  - Crayon portraits of unidentified adults, possibly Medearis family (one large sheet and one smaller fragment), undated (Map-case Drawer 19)
  - One color drawing by 4th grade student Ravi Nair, inspired by Seven Days of Kwanzaa, undated (Map-case Drawer 19)